monarch.co.uk 2019-05-27

# loveholidays privacy policy | loveholidays

loveholidays understands and respects the importance of your privacy and we are committed to doing everything we can to safeguard personal information.

Please read this Privacy Policy to see how we use and protect your personal information. We also have a Cookie Policy which explains how we use cookies and other similar technologies. From time to time, we may make changes to these policies, so please re-visit these pages regularly if you want to keep up to date with any changes we’ve made 

Our Privacy Policy covers all the platforms through which you choose to interact with us, including our mobile-enabled and social media sites. By giving us your personal information, you agree to the transfer, storing or processing of your data in accordance with this policy. 

By making a booking or submitting any personal information via our channels, you are agreeing to us handling your personal information as set out below. If you do not agree to us using your personal information in these ways, unfortunately we can’t process your booking and you shouldn’t use our sites. 

## What kind of personal information do we collect?

When you book through us, you need to provide certain information such as your name, address, e-mail, phone number and payment information. If you happen to fill in the booking pages but for some reason don’t actually complete the booking, you will still be considered to have provided us with your information.

If you contact us, whether by phone, e-mail or another method, you’ll be asked to provide certain information. This is likely to include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number so we can respond to you appropriately.

There are also other instances when you’ll provide us with information, for example if you register to manage your booking via our website, leave a review, enter one of our competitions or complete a survey.

## Information you give to us about others in your party

If you’re booking with others or for someone else, you will have to give us their information as well, for example their name and date of birth. It’s your responsibility to ensure that they are aware that you have done so, and also accept how we use and process their information as well as yours.

## What information do we collect automatically?

When you visit our sites we automatically collect certain information such as the device IP address, the date and time you visited, the hardware, software or particular browser used and information about your visit, including any pages you viewed and interacted with. We do this automatically, even when you don’t actually make a booking.

If you’re using a mobile device to reach us, we keep data that identifies your device, location details and any specific settings. For more information on this, please see our Cookies Policy. 

## Information we get from others

We might also get information about you from other sources, such as your Service Providers, affiliates and other third-parties like credit reference agencies, payment processors, search engines or social media sites. We may use this information with other information you provide in order to complete or process your booking. We will notify you when we receive information about you from them and the purposes for which we intend to use that information.

## What exactly do we do with your personal information?

Your personal information could be used in the following ways: 

**Processing your bookings:** Put simply, we have to use your personal information to ensure the services you’ve selected, which may include flights, hotels, transport, insurance and other ancillary products, are provided to you. We need certain information about you and your party so we can fulfil the contractual obligations when you make a booking.

**User Accounts:** The information that you provide when you set up an account allows us to provide you with additional services including the ability to manage your bookings, personal settings and access to special offers. 

**To communicate with you about your booking:** We’ll need to contact you using the email or telephone number you provided to give you information relevant to your arrangements. For example, to confirm your booking, notification of any changes, security alerts, administrative messages about your arrangements and reminders.

**Customer Services:** You can contact us at any time, whether this is a general query, a question about your booking or to report an issue. You can do this through Manage My Booking on our website, by telephone or via social media. We’ll use the information that you’ve given us to answer any questions and respond to your query or other queries you might have in the future. If you do contact us by telephone, your call may be recorded and reviewed for quality and training purposes. Recordings are only kept for a limited period and then automatically deleted, unless we’ve got a legitimate interest in keeping them for a longer period. 

**Personalisation of your experience:** We sometimes use your data to enable us to show you the most relevant products and services we think you’ll be interested in, such as the best deals and special offers for destinations you like or have been to previously.

**Marketing:** Where you make a booking, or in any other case, if you have opted-in or signed-up, we may contact you with information about other products and services that we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about and we think may interest you based on your personal information. Don’t worry, you can opt-out of these emails at any time.

**Promotional Activities:** If you take part in any of our promotions (such as surveys or competitions) we will need to use the information you provide to run these promotions. 

**Improving our services:** Sometimes we might use your data to help us improve the quality and functionality of our services. This could include eliminating bugs in our system, data analysis, testing, and for statistical and survey purposes, all of which helps us improve the service we offer. 

**Security:** We may use your data as part of the efforts to keep our sites (and the information you provide to us) safe and secure, and to prevent fraud or unauthorised access/use of our sites.

**Fraudulent Claims:** We may use your personal information in order to prevent, detect or defend any claims/actions we believe to be potentially fraudulent or detrimental to our legitimate interests.

**Legal and regulatory compliance:** We might need to use your information in relation to any legal disputes, regulatory, compliance or criminal investigations, or if necessary to enforce our rights.

When we process your information as described above, we will be relying on one or more of the following legal rights:

**Performance of a contract:** We need to use your information to carry out the contract that you have with us and your Service Providers. We’ll use the information that you provide us when making a booking to conclude and process the reservations with the relevant third-party Service Providers. 

**Consent:** You may, through your action(s) of providing us your details, consent to us sending you marketing and promotional material. If you do kindly give us this consent, we’ll rely on this consent when contacting you. You can always withdraw your consent at any time by simply unsubscribing – just follow the unsubscribe link in the email and it’s done.

**Legitimate interest:** We may use your information for our own legitimate interest, for example to provide you with the most relevant content on our site or to promote new services and for certain administrative and legal purposes. If you fail to complete a purchase, we may send you some follow-up emails to try and help you, or seek your feedback or offer you alternative products related to your selection.

**Business transaction:** We may use your data in connection with a business transaction such as the sale of a part or the whole of our business. 

## How do we store your data?

Any information that you provide is stored on secure servers and all payment transactions are encrypted. Only authorised personnel are permitted to access your information in the course of their work with us. Whilst we do our best to protect your information, no information transferred over the internet or stored electronically can be guaranteed to be completely secure and you provide your information to us at your own risk.

We’ll only retain your information for a reasonable period of time, or for so long as either you or the law allows.

When you pay for your holiday, we don’t store your card details – instead we use an encrypted authorisation ‘token’ issued by your payment provider to collect the payment, or remaining payments if you chose to pay by instalments. 

## When do we share your data with third parties?

In certain circumstances we may share the information you provide to us with organisations outside of loveholidays. The third parties who we might share your data with include: 

**Service Providers:** If you make a booking, we’ll have to share your booking data with the third parties, such as hoteliers, airlines, insurers and transfer providers, to complete your booking contract. The data shared may include your name and the names and ages of any guests travelling with you, any preferences or special requests you told us about when you made your booking and your contact details. If you contact us with a query about your booking, we may pass this on to our providers if they are needed to answer you.

Due to the nature of our business and the arrangements you have chosen, it may be necessary for your data to be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") and may not be subject to the same level of data protection controls as within the EEA. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is handled securely.

**Third party support services:** These includes anyone who provides support services or functions on our behalf, including payment card processing, business analytics, review agencies, advertising and customer support services. This may be to send you marketing material on our behalf or to collate information that can be analysed to improve our service. They have access to and may collect information only as required to perform their agreed functions and are not permitted to share or use information for any other purpose.

**Payment Processors and other financial institutions:** When you make a payment on your booking, we use a third-party payment processor to take your payment. If you request a chargeback on your booking, it may be necessary for us to share certain details with the payment processor and the relevant financial institution, so they can manage the chargeback. This may include a copy of your booking confirmation, financial details and the IP address that was used to make your booking. 

**Referring websites:** If you were referred to our site via another webpage, we may share some information about you with that referring website so that they can contact you about their products and services, which may include Google Analytics. 

**Business Affiliates:** We may share your data with our business affiliates with whom we offer relevant joint services. This may include other agencies and advertising networks. We do this in order to maximise the services that we provide you and so they may contact you directly about their relevant products and services that may interest you. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time. 

**Law enforcement authorities:** We will disclose personal information insofar as it is required by law or where we believe it is necessary for the prevention, detection or prosecution of potentially criminal acts, including for fraud, immigration, customs, security or anti-terrorism purposes. 

Please note that whilst we have procedures and security features to protect your information from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage, we don’t control the privacy practices of any of these third-parties or your Service Providers and we would encourage you to review their own privacy policies where appropriate.

Furthermore, any information that you provide directly to your Service Providers or other suppliers is not covered under this Privacy Policy and we would urge to check their own privacy policies before handing over any personal information. 

**What rights do you have in relation to your personal information?**

You have the following rights in relation to the personal information that we hold about you: 

You may request a copy of the personal information we are keeping about you by submitting a Data Subject Access Request to us at the below address. 

You may ask that we correct any inaccuracies in the data, ask us to transfer it to another party or provide it to you for transfer it to another party yourself. 

You can ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes at any time by sending a request to the below address or clicking ‘unsubscribe’ on any of the emails that we send to you. Alternatively you can also email [unsubscribe@loveholidays.com](mailto:unsubscribe@loveholidays.com) and it will be done for you. We will let you know if we intend to use your data for marketing purposes. 

You have the right to request that we delete all personal information that we hold about you. If there is no other reason beside you providing your consent for us to hold your data, we will delete it upon receiving your request. 

If you would like to exercise any of your above rights please contact us at [privacy@loveholidays.com](mailto:privacy@loveholidays.com), writing ‘Data Subject Access Request’ in the subject line. We will deal with any requests we receive in accordance with the relevant UK Data Protection laws. 

## What about data that is collected through a mobile device?

Mobile devices can be used to access our services, as well as versions of our regular website that have been optimised for mobile and tablet browsing. These mobile sites work in a similar way to our main website. Sometimes we make use of something known as cross-device tracking, which allows us to track user behaviour across different devices. We use this to optimise the service that we provide you and for marketing activities, so advertisements shown to you on other websites may be offered based on your activities on linked devices (please see our Cookie Policy for further information on this). 

## How do we treat personal information of children?

You are only allowed to book through our site if you are over 18 years of age. We only process information about children with the consent of the parents or legal guardians. 

## Who exactly is responsible for processing personal information that is collected under the policy?

We Love Holidays Limited controls the processing of data over its sites – in legal terms, this means that We Love Holidays Limited is the Data Controller for the purposes of UK Data Protection laws.

## How can you contact us?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or wish to exercise any of your rights under it, please contact us at: 

Email: [privacy@loveholidays.com](mailto:privacy@loveholidays.com)

Post: Should be sent for the attention of the Legal & Compliance Department to:

5th Floor   
3 Shortlands  
Hammersmith  
London  
W6 8DA

This page was updated 24 May 2018
